In India they were all waiting for the monsoons
在印度 他們都在等待雨季到來
and they are so worried
而且很擔心
because the rain did not come.
因為雨一直沒來
So, I was giving bandhan to the rain and it came here
所以 我剛才正在班丹下雨 它來到了這裡
And now also they have  told,
現在他們也在電視上說了
But first in Italy!
但首先下在義大利
I was told that in Italy you needed rain very much
我聽說義大利也非常需要下雨
and the first rain you had,
幾天前是第一場雨
Because all the understanding
因為我們的農民
of the problems of our farmers is there.
對問題的理解就在那裡
And the rain, you see, is so kind
你知道 雨是如此的善解人意
that it works at the right time.
它在準確的時間工作
I am surprised
我對這雨如此快速的回饋 和順從感到驚喜
Today is a great day, for all of us,  because
今天對我們所有人來說 都是很好的一天
and remembering all the great Gurus
並記住所有來到這個世界上 偉大的導師們
So many of them were [there].
他們中的很多人都來過
And they tried their level best
盡他們最大的努力
to explain to humanity what is spirituality.
向人類解釋什麼是靈性
But it’s such a disparity that people never understood
但是人們理解偏差
that spirituality is the most important thing we need.
不理解靈性是我們所需要的 最重要的事情
That we have to be one with the Divine Power.
我們必須與上天的力量合而為一
All their endeavours have been in the wrong direction.
他們所有的努力都走向了錯誤的方向
First of course they were very intelligent, more than animals,
首先當然他們非常聰明 遠高於動物
and started seeking, not the truth,
並開始尋求 不是真理
but some sort of a self
而是某種自我解脫
self-progress.
自我進步
And in that they lost that they have to first seek spirituality,
因為他們迷失了 他們必須首先尋求靈性
which is the most important thing.
這是最重要的事情
But, we had two types of journeys:
但是 我們有兩種類型的旅程
one is through the left side or another through the right side.
一個是通過左脈 另一個是通過右脈
In India, I don’t know why,
在印度 我不知道為什麼
we had lots of people who went into the jungles and became saints
我們有很多人進入叢林而成為聖人
but they were doing right side tapasya.
但他們做的是右脈的苦行
That is, going into the five elements
也就是說 他們一個個進入五大元素
Of course there is truth in it, no doubt.
毫無疑問 當然這裡面有真相
You have seen how a candle
你看過一支蠟燭怎樣
how a candle tells you as to what is your position inside:
蠟燭怎樣告訴你內在的狀況
if you are possessed or if you are not,
如果你被附身或沒被附身
a candle can tell you – can you imagine?
蠟燭可以告訴你 你能想像嗎
Candle is so much knowledgable.
蠟燭是如此有學問
Supposing you have a heart, heart trouble –
假設你有心臟病
the candle will show.
蠟燭會顯示出來
And if you treat yourself with a candle, you can cure yourself.
如果你治療自己 你可以治癒自己
So, it is so sensitive
所以 它是如此敏感
not that it can cure, but also so competent,
不但可以治癒 而且也很有能力
not that it shows you that you are sick and you have problems
它不但可以告訴你你生病了 你有問題
but that it is competent to cure you.
而且有能力治癒你
Thats why, in India, Agni was worshipped,
這就是為什麼在印度 火神被崇拜
this  light was worshipped,
光元素被崇拜
the fire was worshipped, that was worshipped first.
火被崇拜 這些首先被崇拜
They must have discovered that the fire knows everything,
他們一定發現火知道一切
so the inner, inner awareness of all these elements,
所以所有元素的內在知覺
they knew about it and thats why they worshipped those elements.
他們知道這一點 這就是為什麼他們崇拜這些元素
So before the Puja they used to call all the Deities who belonged
因此 在普祭之前他們會召喚 所有屬於這些元素的神祇
But that turned out to be right sided movement.
但人們把它弄成右脈的活動
Without the left side right side is very dangerous.
沒有左脈 只有右脈是非常危險的
If you don’t have right side of course
如果你沒有右脈
development of your left side.
發展你的左脈
That is what, to begin with, we had in Sahaja Yoga.
這就是我們在霎哈嘉瑜伽中 首先開始的事情
Left side is compassion, is love, universal feeling,
左脈是慈悲 是愛 是普遍的感覺
which are described you know it, in the Devi Mahatmyam,
這在《女神頌》中被描述過 你知道的
that the Goddess resides within you as so many things.
女神以許多形相存在於你之內
She resides within you as shraddha.
祂以信心 睡眠
as, She resides in you as sleep,
幻象 迷惑的形相
She resides in you as illusion, bhranti.
存在於你之內
All kinds of things are there on the left-hand side,
在左脈 祂以各種各樣的形相存在
which are already described.
這已經描述過了
And when I told you about Sahaja Yoga,
當我向你們講述霎哈嘉瑜伽的時候
I wanted to make your left side very strong.
我想讓你們的左脈變得強壯
Those who, people who, took to right side
那些被帶到右脈的人
became very aggressive people, and they had mastered
變得非常有侵略性 他們已經掌握了
the essence of these five elements, that’s alright. But
這五大元素的本質 沒關係
so much so that they used to curse people, curse them.
甚至他們過去常常詛咒別人 詛咒他們
They used to say things which were not kind;
他們經常說不友善的事
and they didn’t believe in the universality.
他們不相信整體存有
It was such a dangerous thing that they took.
這是非常危險的事情 以致於他們被帶到右脈
In Indian shastras you can see many incidents
在印度典籍中 你可以看到許多人們
where people gave a curse, sharp, very common.
詛咒別人 說話尖銳的事件 非常普遍
All these gurus used to curse a person,
所有這些導師過去常常詛咒別人
because they had no compassion, no love, nothing but they had powers
因為他們沒有慈悲心 沒有愛心 什麼也沒有只有右脈的力量
that those people who have right side,
那些右脈的人
who go only on the right side without the bhakti,
只處在右脈 沒有虔敬的人
without the blessings of the Divine,
沒有上天的祝福
can become rakshasas actually,
實際上會成為羅刹魔
can become a great danger for humanity.
會成為人類巨大的危險
This is a very serious thing:
這是一個非常嚴重的事情
through your intelligence, through your thinking power,
通過你的智商 通過你的思維能力
your ego can go to any limit
你的自我可以達到任何極限
and create problems within you.
並在你內在製造問題
Now the ultimate of this problem is,
現在這個問題的最終結果是
we have seen is, are many diseases,
我們已經看到 有很多疾病
which are absolutely incurable.
是絕對無法治癒的
Even some people, right-sided, some people,
甚至有些右脈的人
can get a kind of a cancer called blood cancer.
會得一種叫做血癌的癌症
And this blood cancer, now we have cured it,
而這種血癌 現在我們能治好了
but even if it is cured you can go back
但即使它被治癒 你也可能回到
to that kind of aggressiveness
那種侵略性
thinking that you are very right.
以為你是非常正確的
Such people always try to find faults with others,
這樣的人總是試圖找別人的錯
that such and such person is not good, he’s doing harm,
這樣的人 那樣的人不好 他在傷害別人
or any way they can find faults with others, not with themselves.
或者無論如何他們都能找到 他人的錯誤 而不是自己的錯誤
Their attention is outside, not on themselves.
他們的注意力總是在外面 而不是在他們自己身上
They never see what’s wrong with them,
他們從來看不到自己有什麼問題
but they always see what’s wrong with others.
但他們總能看出別人的問題
By doing that, you see, they are climbing the ladder
以這樣的方式 你們知道 他們正在爬上一個可怕的
of a horrible right side, which can give you horrible diseases.
右脈的梯子 那會給你帶來可怕的疾病
As I’ve told you, first is the blood cancer.
正如我告訴過你們的 首先就是血癌
If you get rid of the blood cancer then
如果你擺脫了血癌
you can get into another problems. Nowadays there’s a very famous
你可能會陷入另外的問題
This is also the side of the right side;
這也是右脈的問題
because if you don’t have that bhakti, that humility,
因為如果你沒有那種虔敬 謙卑
that blessings of the Goddess,
沒有女神的祝福
you can develop all such horrible diseases
你會得所有這些可怕的疾病
which are not only fatal,
這些疾病不僅是致命的
but also very injurious to others.
也是非常傷人的
So by being right-sided you do not progress.
所以處於右脈 你不會進步
You can become a big ascetic, they call it,
你可以成為一個別人口中的 大苦行僧
who can curse others,
能詛咒別人
who can put them into troubles,
能讓別人陷入困境
think that that is a great power – it is not!
認為那是一種強大的力量 並非如此
It is not at all.
完全不是這樣
Because, though you are not suppressed
因為 雖然你沒有被
by other powers, negative powers,
其他負面力量壓制
but your own power takes your life.
但是你自己的力量奪走了你的生命
So Kundalini, when it is arisen,
所以昆達利尼 當它升起時
the best thing is to go to the left side,
最好的事情是走到左脈
not criticising others, not talking ill of others,
不批評別人 不說別人的壞話
but seeing within you, what’s wrong.
但是看看你的內在 有什麼問題
Find out what is the matter with you.
找出你的問題
First it starts with self-importance,
首先 它始於妄自尊大
that “I am a very important person,”
我是一個非常重要的人
and with this self-importance you go on
因為這種妄自尊大
But because of your right-side movement,
但是由於你的右脈活動
you can become very successful.
你可以變得非常成功
Hitler was the climax of that.
希特勒就是這樣的極端
And that’s how people start taking to very, very cruel things.
隨後人們開始做 非常非常殘酷的事情
Nowadays, I think that some people are
如今 我認為有些人
ruling  everywhere with their right side.
正用他們的右脈統治各處
We do not have people who are using their left side.
我們沒有人使用他們的左脈
And whenever they use their left side they are called as saints.
每當他們使用他們左脈時 他們被稱為聖人
Now you all have the powers of the left side.
現在你們都擁有左脈的力量
Some of you do have little bit right side also, doesn’t matter.
你們當中有些人也有一點點偏右 沒關係
Now I would say that you have achieved
現在我想說你已經取得了
your left side mastery:
左脈的成就
Kundalini awakening is there, you are one with the Divine.
昆達裡尼已經喚醒 你和上天的力量合一
Now you can come to the right side and know about right side,
現在你可以來到右脈 瞭解右脈
and try to express your right side.
並嘗試表達你的右脈
You can express it not by dominating others but dominating yourself.
你可以表達它 不是通過控制別人而是通過控制自己
By self-examination.
通過自省
By understanding what’s wrong with you. Why do you behave like that?
通過瞭解你自己的缺點 你為什麼這麼做
Why do you trouble others? Why do you overpower others?
你為什麼要麻煩他人 你為什麼壓倒他人
Such people will always, I have seen, organise
我見過這樣的人 他們組織事情
and arrange, and do this and do that.
安排事情 做這做那
Instead of organising themselves they’ll organise others.
他們不管理自己 卻管理他人
These things complicate.
把事情變得複雜
But if you have love and if you have bhakti,
但如果你有愛 如果你有虔誠奉獻
you can very, very easily
你可以非常容易
dominate  others in a very different manner.
以非常不同的方式主導其他人
It is not that you dominate by cruelty,
不是通過殘忍管制
by oppression, but you dominate with your love.
不是通過壓迫 而是你通過愛來主導
And you don’t want to dominate,
你不想宰製
but easily people get very much succumbed
但人們很容易就順服於
to love and to magnanimity, to generosity.
愛 寬容和慷慨
So all these qualities you must first develop within yourself:
因此 你首先必須在自己內在 發展所有這些品質
is the left-side problem, that – you should be very peaceful,
這是左脈的問題 你應該很平和
you should give love to others, you should be generous,
你應該關愛別人 你應該慷慨
you should be kind, and see how much it means.
你應該友善 看看它能花多少錢
I’ve seen some people who are extremely rude,
我見過一些極其粗魯的人
they can be rude to anyone, that’s their nature,
他們對任何人都很粗魯 這是他們的本性
which they should overcome with the left side.
他們應該用左脈來克服這些
Rudeness is not the sign of a saint.
粗魯並不是聖人的標誌
A saint is extremely peaceful,
聖人極其平和
and never gets rude with others.
從不會對別人粗魯
So the introspection should work first of all,
因此首先應該內省
“Where are we wrong? What wrong things we are doing?
我們哪裡錯了 我們做了什麼錯事
What is our style?”
我們的風格是什麼
Once you discover that your style is already left-side,
一旦你發現你的風格 已經有左脈的力量了
then you should take to right side
你就可以來到右脈
and possess the power of right side.
並擁有右脈的力量
What are the powers of right side now
現在右邊的力量是什麼
which are achieved through the left-side perfection?
哪些是通過完善左脈可以達成的
We have some very great Gurus on this line.
我們在這裡有一些非常偉大的導師
One of them was Raja Janaka.
其中一個是拉賈.迦納克
He was a ruler of a country,
他是一個國家的統治者
and a very well-known ruler and everything; but still, still,
一個非常出名的統治者 但仍然
though He was so generous and good and everything,
他是如此慷慨 善良
but at the same time He was a great monarch,
同時 他是一位偉大的君主
great king of those days,
當時偉大的國王
very much known for His impartiality,  for His statesmanship
因其公正而聞名 因為他的政治才能
and all kinds of beautiful things He did for His
以及他為國家所做的各種好事而出名
He could not get disturbed with anything.
他不會被任何事情打擾
And people never understood
人們不理解
why the greatest of greatest saints used to bow to Him.
為什麼最偉大的聖人 都常常向他鞠躬行禮
What was so great? Though He was a king, He was living so lavishly
為什麼呢 儘管他是國王 生活奢華
and He had so many of ornaments and
儘管他有很多飾物
also conveyances and all that;
和很多交通工具和所有這些
because nothing was above Him,
但因為沒有什麼淩駕於他
He was so detached with everything.
他不執著於這一切
He had everything, but He was so detached.
他擁有一切 但他如此不執著
That’s a very good example of a person
這是一個掌握左脈力量的典範
Like that we had many people later on also,
我們後來也有很多人像這樣
one after another, who were extremely, extremely rich,
一個接一個 他們極其富有
but inside they were
但他們的內在
Nothing disturbed them, nothing made them feel greater or happier.
沒有什麼能打擾他們 沒有什麼讓他們感到更偉大或更快樂
No position, no power was to them great.
沒有什麼名 利對他們來說是巨大的
This is a complete emancipation of human beings,
你們是獲得自覺的靈
that you are realised soul.
這是人類的徹底解脫
You should be fully equipped with compassion love and understanding.
你們應該充滿慈悲 愛和諒解
But at the same time, it should be expressed in the right way.
但與此同時 它應該以正確的方式表達
For example, we can say Christ, He’s another example.
例如 我們可以說基督 祂是另一個例子
Though He was an Incarnation, still
雖然祂是一個降世神祇
the amount of forgiveness and love He has for people is tremendous.
但祂依然對人們有巨大的寬恕和愛
But at the same time,
但與此同時
He used to go on the mountains and preach about spirituality.
祂過去常常去山上宣講靈性
Those were not very safe times,
在那個時代不是很安全
because people didn’t like anybody talking like that.
因為人們不喜歡任何人那樣說
They hated Him because He talked about God.
他們恨祂 因為祂談到了上帝
And what they did to Him you know very well.
他們對祂所做的事情 你們很清楚
Doesn’t matter.
沒關係
Though they crucified Him, still
雖然他們把祂釘死在十字架上
Reason is, He was, He was no doubt an Incarnation,
原因是 毫無疑問祂是一個降世神祇
but still He went all out to give His achievements or
但祂仍然全力以赴地把祂的成就
He went all over the places, He had no facilities,
祂走遍了各個地方 沒有任何工具
but still He went out to many people
但祂還是見了很多人
and tried to save them.
並試圖拯救他們
This was the right-side movement.
這是右脈的活動
That means Sahaja Yogis can also become right-sided,but like Christ.
這意味著霎哈嘉瑜伽士 也可以變得右脈 但要像基督一樣
Otherwise if they are right-sided
否則 如果他們是右脈的
they’ll organise, they’ll do all kinds of things,
他們會組織 他們會做各種各樣的事情
and have problems of the right side.
並有右脈的問題
That’s why I want you to avoid the right side.
這就是為什麼我要你們避免右脈
But once you are fully a left-sided master of Sahaja Yoga,
但是 一旦你完全掌握 霎哈嘉瑜伽的左脈力量
then it’s very, very much needed
接著必須要成為
to be a complete personality of spirituality,
一個整合的靈性人格
that you should take to right-side movement.
你應該有右脈的行動
And what is the right-side movement is the collectivity.
右脈的行動就是集體性
Should not be satisfied with what you have got.
不應該滿足於你們所擁有的
It’s very easy
人們很容易感覺
to feel, “Oh, now we have got realisation, now what is there?
哦 現在我們已經得到自覺 還有什麼呢
We are on top of the world!” That’s not so.
我們處於世界巔峰 並非如此
You have to go out, talk to people.
你們必須走出去 告知人們
They will insult you, they’ll trouble you,
他們會侮辱你 會麻煩你
they’ll do all kinds of things.
會做各種各樣的事情
But you are already a person, already a realised soul.
但你已經是另外一種人 一個已經得到自覺的靈
You can listen to them, what they are saying;
你可以傾聽他們 聽他們在說什麼
you will not ask for anything, but you’d like to do good to them.
你不要求任何東西 你只是想對他們好
This is also a compassion,
這也是一種慈悲心
that you don’t want to keep your realisation to yourself,
你不想把自覺留給自己
but you want to do it
而是想分享給別人
for others also so that they also get realisation,
讓他們也得到自覺
it’s very important. If you do not feel that way,
這很重要 如果你沒有那樣的感受
the pity for people who haven’t got realisation,
不同情那些還沒得到自覺的人
think of the times you were not realised.
想想你還沒得到自覺的時候
These people are also not realised and they are having a bad time,
那些沒得到自覺的人 正在經歷艱難時刻
they can be in for any trouble.
他們會有麻煩的
So now, it’s not that if you have got realisation
所以現在 不是如果你們得到了自覺
you settle down with it – no, that’s not the way;
就自己安頓下來 不是這樣
but you should go all out to see
你們都應該走出去
that you give realisation to others, and save them.
給別人帶自覺 去拯救他們
You all have got realisation not for your sake,
你們都得到了自覺 不是只為了自己
it’s not limited for you, but it is meant for others,
局限於自己 也是為了他人
that you have to give it to others.
帶給他人自覺
And as soon as you’ll start giving it to others you’ll be amazed,
一旦你們開始給別人自覺 你們會驚喜
so many qualities in you will come up;
你內在那麼多美好的品質開始顯現
because when you see others, you find
因為當你們看別人
what do they need, what you have to give,  how you have to give.
他們需要什麼 你們必須給予什麼 必須怎麼給予
You can become anything, you can become a poet,
你們可以成為任何人 可以成為詩人
you can become a writer, you can, anything can you become,
可以成為作家 為了能面對其他人
in case you face others.
你們可以成為任何人
Then it comes as a reaction within you, all these qualities develop,
然後作為一種回應 所有這些品質在你之內開始發展
and you become a very good, I should say, artist.
你成為一個很好的 我應該說 藝術家
This is only possible if you meet other people
只有當你們面見他人
and talk to them about Sahaja Yoga,
跟他們談霎哈嘉瑜伽
and tell them about your Self-realisation.
跟他們談你的自覺的時候 這才可能發生
I know there will be problems, I know. That is true.
我知道會有問題 我知道 這是真的
There will be people who will oppose you, say
會有人反對你們
But that’s the thing you should achieve,
但那是你們應該達成的事情
is to meet people, talk to them
面見他人 與他們交談
and start telling them about Self-realisation you have to save them.
並開始告訴他們自覺 你們必須拯救他們
That’s important.
這很重要
But first of all you should know that you should have no right-sided
但首先你們應該知道 你們應該沒有右脈的問題
A person who is spiritual is supposed
一個屬靈的人
or accepted to be a very humble person.
是人們認為或公認 是一個非常謙卑的人
Of course because he is humble, people will take advantage of him,
當然因為他很謙卑 人們會利用他
say all kinds of things, it’s alright, is a part of the game.
說各種各樣的話 沒關係 這是遊戲的一部分
But, he doesn’t mind, he doesn’t mind anything.
但是他不介意 他不介意任何事
Anything that comes his way, he doesn’t mind.
無論他遇到任何事 他都不介意
But what is the main thing is that he has compassion.
但最主要的是他有慈悲心
His compassion that he had before from the left side is now expanded
他之前來自左脈的慈悲心開始擴展
and he wants to save the people.
他想要拯救人們
People don’t have food, is alright, it’s a big complication;
人們沒有食物 好吧 這是個難題
if people are starving is another;
如果人們挨餓是另一種情況
but if they do not get spirituality,
但如果他們得不到靈性
what’s the use of their human life,
那成為人又有什麼用
why did they evolve to this state?
為什麼他們進化到這個狀態
They are evolved from animal state,
他們是從動物的狀態
from the worst possible to a human state.
從最糟糕的條件進化到人類的狀態
And now if they do not get their realisation,
現在 如果他們得不到自覺
that means this is worse than starving,
這意味著這比饑餓更糟
worse than all kinds of poverty,
比各種貧困更糟
worse than all kinds of diseases and troubles.
比各種疾病和麻煩更糟
So why not try to give them realisation?
那麼為什麼不嘗試給他們自覺呢
Why not see that you give them realisation?
為什麼看不到你們給他們自覺
But first and foremost thing, as I said,
但首要的 正如我所說
that in the left you should be very strong.
你們的左脈應該非常強大
You shouldn’t start doing it because you have got your realisation,
你們不應該因為自己得到了自覺
you can give realisation.
就開始帶自覺
So you should not start doing it
應該等到你們的左脈加強以後
unless and until you have strengthened your left side.
才開始帶自覺
Such a person is extremely humble,
這樣的人極其謙卑
extremely straight, doesn’t grudge about anything,
極其坦率 對任何事情都不抱怨
doesn’t grumble about anything,
什麼都不抱怨
and can adjust itself into any circumstance.
並可以適應任何情況
It is not attached to anything.
它不執著於任何東西
It’s an automatic detachment, it doesn’t have to detach.
這是一個自動的不執著 它不是被迫的
You may do anything for that person,
你可以為那個人做任何事
you may try to get anything for that person, it’s alright.
你可以嘗試為那個人得到任何東西 沒關係
That person will accept, no doubt,
毫無疑問 那個人會接受
but without any attachment to anything.
但沒有任何執著
Such a detached person is the one who can work it out,
這樣一個不執著的人可以成就
all kinds of propagation of Sahaja Yoga.
霎哈嘉瑜伽的各種傳播
Today that is the greatest need of the world,
今天這世界上最大的需求
that we have to have more Sahaja Yogis.
是我們必須有更多的霎哈嘉瑜伽士
Now, people are so shy to do that,
現在有些人會很害羞這樣做
it’s very surprising.
這非常令人驚訝
But I have seen people who don’t have any truth,
但我看到有些人 他們沒有任何真理
who have all kinds of bad gurus,
跟過各種壞導師
get after others, try to spread their false ideas.
卻到處找人試圖傳播他們錯誤的想法
But Sahaja Yogis, why should they feel,
但霎哈嘉瑜伽士
why should they feel shy, I don’t understand.
他們為什麼覺得害羞 我不明白
So, talk about this to everyone, bring them to Sahaja Yoga.
所以 向每個人談論這個 把他們帶到霎哈嘉瑜伽來
Is a very important day, because as a Guru puja,
今天是非常重要的一天 因為作為一個導師普祭
they say that a guru cannot give anything to you.
他們說導師不能給你們什麼東西
But I can give you the advice,
但我可以給你們建議
and the advice that you enlarge your heart,
建議你們擴展你們的心
you become humble, and try to spread Sahaja Yoga
變得謙卑 並嘗試謙卑地傳播霎哈嘉瑜伽
That is extremely important.
這極其重要
If you can do that, then you’ll do full justice
如果你們能做到這一點 那這一生
Without that you cannot achieve, you cannot achieve,
如果做不到這樣 你們無法實現
the strength of spirituality.
你們無法實現 屬靈的力量
For that you haveto understand that it’s very, very important
為此你們必須明白 這是非常非常重要的
that you should give Sahaja Yoga a full chance,through your wisdom.
你們應該通過你們的智慧 給霎哈嘉瑜伽一個完全的機會
What I receive [is] mostly the letters are
我收到的大多數信件
that person is doing like that. Forget it!
這個人那樣做 算了吧
All such persons are not important for Sahaja Yoga.
所有這些人對霎哈嘉瑜伽都不重要
But if you start on proper lines you will be amazed,
但如果你開始正確的線路 你會感到驚訝
you’ll meet so many people who want peace of mind,
你會遇到那麼多想要頭腦平和的人
peace of heart and a complete oneness with the Divine.
想要內心平和 想要和上天完全合一的人
They may not accept, they may not say,
他們可能不會接受 他們可能不會說
they might have gone to the wrong people also, possibly.
他們可能也會曾經跟隨錯的人
But despite everything,
但儘管如此
they would like to have a real spiritual peace within themselves.
他們希望在自己內在 擁有真正的靈性平和
Is a very common desire nowadays among people,
現在這是人們非常普遍的願望
but to approach that and to reach that,
但要接近並達到目標
you have to take to a life of a very simple personality.
你必須過上一種 有非常簡單人格的生活
You see, if you are so much interested in money,
你看 如果你對錢很感興趣
or if you are so much interested in your so-called powers
或者如果你對你所謂的權力 或你的野心感興趣
But if you are interested in your compassion
但如果你對你的慈悲心
and understanding about today’s world,
和理解今天的世界感興趣
how it is in a turmoil: why?
它是如何陷入混亂的 為什麼
Because of the human beings being in the wrong.
因為人類自己處於錯誤之中
What we have to do is to pass them the knowledge of the Divine.
我們要做的 就是傳遞給他們上天的知識
That should be your desire,
這應該是你的願望
and that is what you’ll feel very much comfortable with.
這會讓你感到非常舒服
All other desires, all other wants are,
所有其他的欲望 所有其他的願望
as you say, it’s very transitory.
正如你所說 都是非常短暫的
One desire is to spread Sahaja Yoga,
傳播霎哈嘉瑜伽的願望
is so beautiful that you go on working on it,
是如此美麗 以至於你持續致力於此
and every time you do that,
每次你這樣做
you will be so joyous and happy,
你會如此喜悅和幸福
you’ll have no problems of any kind.
你不會有任何問題
That’s the sign of greatness of Sahaja Yoga,
這是霎哈嘉瑜伽偉大的標誌
and I want you all to become like that.
我希望你們都成為那樣
As today’s day is great, because
今天的日子很偉大
and who tried to lead us.  What they did,
他們試著引導我們
all of them tried to spread the truth all over the world.
他們所做的一切 都嘗試向全世界傳播真理
They suffered a lot, they had problems, so many problems,
他們遭受了很多苦難 他們遇到問題 很多問題
but they worked very hard in every way to spread Sahaja Yoga
但他們非常努力地工作 以各種方式傳播霎哈嘉瑜伽
and talk about God anddivinity.
並談論上帝與神性
All that is what today you have to give Me,
綜上 今天你們要給我一個承諾
you can tell them about Sahaja Yoga.
你要告訴他們霎哈嘉瑜伽
Not that it’s important but it’s absolutely
並不是說它很重要
immediate need of the world.
而是說這是世界迫切需要的
If you understand this point,
如果你明白這一點
that at this time, why are you in this world
你為什麼在這個時候來到這個世界上
and what is the need of the world,
什麼是這個世界的需要
you will immediately start feeling the responsibility.
你會立即開始感受到這個責任
Whether you are a man or a woman is not important.
你是男人還是女人並不重要
Go all out to preach, think,
全力以赴地去宣講 思考
make people understand about Sahaja  Yoga
讓人們瞭解霎哈嘉瑜伽
in every way that is possible,
以各種可能的方式
and I think, then, you will become complete as gurus.
如此一來 我想你才能完全成為一個導師
If Sahaja Yoga is just with you, you cannot be a guru.
如果霎哈嘉瑜伽只存在於你自身 你就不能成為一個導師
‘Guru’ also doesn’t mean that you go on preaching about Sahaja Yoga
導師 也不意味著 你一直講述霎哈嘉瑜伽
talking about Sahaja Yoga, giving lectures about Sahaja Yoga, no!
談論霎哈嘉瑜伽 講授霎哈嘉瑜伽 不
It means the one who gives realisations to others.
它意味著給他人帶自覺
How many people you give realisation is the thing,
關鍵的是你給多少人帶去自覺
not to be counted,  but to be felt within like the ripples,
不要去數算 但要在內在感受
waves of the Ocean of Love in your heart.
像漣漪一樣 你心中那愛的海洋的浪花
So beautiful it is to see that people get realisation
看到人們得到自覺
and are immersed in the joy of spirituality.
並融入到靈性的喜悅中 是多麼美好啊
That’s what I want you to do. That’s why I am on this earth.
這就是我想要你們做的 這就是我來到這個世界上的原因
I had to suffer also quite a lot, doesn’t matter:
我不得不也遭受很多苦難 沒關係
so-called sufferings, I was watching it just like a drama.
所謂的苦難 我都視作一場戲劇
So it’s ok.
所以沒關係
As long as you do not pay much attention
只要你不太注意
to all these sufferings, what is so great?
只要你不太在意這些苦難 又有什麼了不起的
Now you have seen yesterday a beautiful drama about Mohammad Sahib.
昨天你們已經看了那部 關於默罕默德的精彩戲劇
I always used to think,  and it was such pain, about Him,  that
我以前常想 對祂來說這是多麼痛苦
why they are doing all wrong things? Now,
為什麼人們要做這些錯事
and have understood and made such a beautiful drama out of it.
理解祂並製作了如此美麗的戲劇
I don’t know how far we can propagate this,
我不知道我們可以傳播多遠
but it’s a fact that Mohammad Sahib Himself
但事實上默罕默德自己去世了
His son-in-law was finished.
他的女婿也去世了
And after that, by finishing them,
在他們去世後
they started another horrible thing called Sunnis.
出現了可怕的遜尼派教徒
Now, the Sunnah religion is not near the truth at all,
現在的遜尼派根本遠離真理
it’s some sort of a very aggressive and a very cruel religion,
這是一種非常具有攻擊性 和非常殘忍的宗教
and that started spreading everywhere.
並開始在各地蔓延
In the real Islam religion of Mohammed Sahib was not there.
在真正的穆罕默德伊斯蘭教中 殘忍根本不存在
Those people who killed Him started becoming ‘Islamic’.
那些殺死他的人開始變成 伊斯蘭教徒
So this is also a very wrong thing,
所以這也是一個非常錯誤的事情
that a man who was so great and so much of spirituality
一個如此偉大 如此屬靈的人
was not just accepted,
不被接受
and somebody who killed Him is now accepted.
現在人們接受了一個殺死祂的人
It can happen in anything.
任何事情都可能發生
But the worst it has happened in is Islamic world,
但最糟糕的是發生在伊斯蘭世界
which is very dangerous, and that’s we see
這是非常危險的 我們看到了
that, in the name of God, how many bad things they are doing.
他們以上帝之名 在做著多少壞事
So, try to understand
所以 試著去理解
that it is not the fate of Mohammad Sahib it has happened,
發生的這些事不是默罕默德的命運
it’s not the fate of reality it has happened,
也不是實相的命運
but it’s an eye-opener for all of us to see
但它讓我們所有人都大開眼界
that the Truth is always challenged by untruth.
真理總是被假相所挑戰
And we should stand by the Truth, whatever may happen.
無論發生什麼 我們都應該堅持真理
And a day will come when people will realise
總有一天人們會意識到
that this was a wrong thing they were being,
他們一直以來是錯的
all the time been following,
跟隨著錯誤
and have been doing all kinds of nonsensical things.
且一直在做各種荒謬的事情
All this will work out I am sure, very soon,
所有這一切都會成就 我相信很快就會實現
if My desire is that powerful, I’m sure
如果我的願望那麼強大
May God bless you.
願上帝保佑你